Guide to the Claude McKay Collection
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
Claude McKay collection
1853-1990
1922-1948
JWJ MSS 27
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
12
(22 boxes) ) 1 cold storage
The Claude McKay Collection consists of correspondence, writings, personal papers, photographs and memorabilia documenting the life and work of Claude McKay. Series I, Correspondence, consists of two subseries for General and Publishers Correspondence. There is correspondence with many well known writers and figures in the African American community from the first half of the 20th century, including Langston Hughes, James Weldon Johnson, Carl Van Vechten, Countee Cullen and Harold Jackman. Series II, Writings, contains a variety of writings: articles, essays, short stories, novels, book-length autobiographical and non-fictional work, individual poems and collections of poems, and writings of others. There are holograph and typescript drafts of My Green Hills of Jamaica, and typescript drafts of Harlem: Negro Metropolis, an unpublished novel (Romance in Marseilles), and collections of poems, including The Selected Poems of Claude McKay. Series III, Personal Papers, is organized into eight subseries: Books, Clippings, Financial and Legal Records, Invitations and Announcements, Material Relating to McKay's Death and Burial, Medical and Health Records, Postcards and Other. Series IV, Subject Files, consists chiefly of clippings dating from the 1920s and 1930s on liberal politics, labor issues, race, and the countries in which McKay resided while abroad. Series V, Photographs, consists of five subseries: Family, Snapshots of McKay, Other People, Places and Other. There are photographs from Soviet Russia in the early 1920s, and studio portraits of well known musicians and figures in the African American community. Series VI, Memorabilia, contains clippings, photographs, program material and souvenirs from four separate commemorative events in honor of McKay from 1979-1990.
McKay, Claude, 1890-1948
Immediate Source of Acquisition
The Claude McKay Collection was acquired primarily by purchase and gifts from Ruth Hope McKay Virtue, McKay's daughter, from 1964-1991. Original letters from McKay to others appear to have come into the collection with the original purchase in 1964. Additional gifts have been made by Liliane Blary, Sister Mary Conroy, Wayne Cooper and William Schenck.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Box 21-22: Restricted fragile material. Reference surrogates have been substituted in the main files. For further information consult the appropriate curator.
Folders 697-700 (negatives): Restricted fragile material. Reference surrogates have been substituted in the main files. For further information consult the appropriate curator.
CLAUDE MCKAY (1890-1948)
Claude McKay was a Jamaican-born writer who spent most of his adult life in the United States, Europe and North Africa. He wrote several collections of poetry, novels, short stories, non-fiction and two autobiographical books. He is best known for an early poem, "If We Must Die" (1919), and his first novel, Home to Harlem (1928). He lived in the United States, primarily in New York, from 1913-1919, and then spent most of the next 15 years in England, Russia, France, Spain and Morocco before returning to New York in 1934. He contributed to many liberal and socialist journals, including Sylvia Pankhurst's Worker's Dreadnaught and Max Eastman's The Liberator, and he is commonly identified among the major writers of the Harlem Renaissance. He converted to Catholicism in 1944 and died in Chicago in 1948. See the standard biographical print resources for additional information.
Scope and Contents
The Claude McKay Collection consists of letters, manuscripts, personal papers, subject files, photographs and memorabilia documenting the life and work of the Jamaican born writer Claude McKay. The collection spans the years 1853-1990, with the bulk of the material dating from 1922-1948.
The collection is housed in 21 boxes and organized into six series: Correspondence, Writings, Personal Papers, Subject Files, Photographs and Memorabilia. Boxes 20-21 contain Oversize material and Restricted Fragile Papers.
Series I, Correspondence, is organized into two subseries: General Correspondence and Publishers Correspondence.
General Correspondence, housed in boxes 1-7, consists largely of incoming correspondence. There is correspondence from many well known writers and figures in the African-American community from the first half of the 20th century, including Langston Hughes, Countee Cullen, James Weldon Johnson, Carl Van Vechten, Harold Jackman, and to a lesser extent, Arna Bontemps, Gwendolyn Bennett and Alain Locke. Other writers found in the collection are Nancy Cunard, F. Scott Fitzgerald, Edmund Wilson, Charles Henri Ford, Jacques Roberti, Louis Guilloux, Albert Halper and Ammon Hennacy. There is also correspondence with family and friends, most notably Max Eastman.
Most of the outgoing correspondence in this subseries consists of carbons dating from the mid-late 1930s, after McKay had returned to New York from Morocco. There is correspondence to Sterling A. Brown regarding work with the Federal Writers' Project, and to several others soliciting recommendations for Guggenheim fellowships. There are original letters, however, to Harold Jackman and to Carl Cowl. The correspondence with Jackman dates from the late 1920s, when McKay lived in France, and resumes in the mid 1930s. In early letters McKay often asks for favors, such as books, and the letters touch on a variety of topics, McKay's work and publications, other writers and friends, and race. The correspondence with Cowl, McKay's literary agent from early 1947, deals primarily with the agent's efforts to find publishers for the manuscripts to The Selected Poems of Claude McKay and My Green Hills of Jamaica.
The General subseries includes some third party correspondence, the bulk of which is to Carl Cowl and to McKay's daughter, Ruth Hope McKay Virtue. These letters are arranged by correspondent and noted in the folder description.
The Publishers subseries, housed in box 8, includes McKay's correspondence with publishers and all third party correspondence with publishers previously identified as "publishers miscellaneous." Here too the bulk of the third party correspondence is with Carl Cowl and relates to publication of The Selected Poems of Claude McKay and My Green Hills of Jamaica.
Series II, Writings, is organized into eight subseries: Articles, Essays and Reports, Autobiographical Information, Blurbs, Books, Notes and Notebooks, Poetry, Stories and Writings of Others. The first seven subseries are arranged alphabetically by title. Writings of Others is arranged first by author and then by title.
The Articles, Essays and Reports subseries, housed in box 9, brings together various pieces of non-fiction, most in draft form, as well as a few polemical newspaper articles, dating from the early and late 1930s, in which McKay responds to critics of his literary work and views on labor. Autobiographical Information consists of a long statement on the selection of the original photograph for the book jacket to the 1940 E. P. Dutton publication of Harlem: Negro Metropolis, and includes a list of journals and magazines to which McKay contributed. The Blurbs subseries consists of a single printed advertisement.
The Books subseries, housed in boxes 9-11, brings together McKay's novels, autobiographical writings, and short story and essay compilations. There is a draft of Harlem: Negro Metropolis, and early, revised and final drafts of My Green Hills of Jamaica, McKay's autobiography of his youth, published postumously in 1979. There is also a manuscript entitled "New Novel" which, according to Wayne Cooper's introduction to The Passion of Claude McKay (1973), appears to be a draft of an unpublished novel, "Romance in Marseilles," written in Spain in 1930.
The Notes and Notebooks subseries consists of three holograph notebooks and one folder of loose notes.
Poetry, housed in boxes 11-13, includes manuscripts of published and unpublished collections, as well as drafts and printed versions of individual poems, all arranged alphabetically by title. Most of the individual poems in this subseries appeared in journals and/or published collections and many are also present in the manuscripts for The Selected Poems of Claude McKay.
The Stories subseries includes draft and printed versions of "Dinner in Douarnenez," and the printed version of a collection of stories, translated from the Russian back into English, under the title Trial by Lynching. The Writings of Others subseries brings together all work by other writers, related and unrelated to McKay, and includes articles, reviews, poems and other forms. There are two short printed articles on the subject of cricket, in Australian sources, which may be by McKay or another individual with the same name.
Series III, Personal Papers, housed in boxes 14-16, is organized into eight subseries: Books, Clippings, Financial and Legal Records, Invitations and Announcements, Material Relating to McKay's Death and Burial, Medical and Health Records, Postcards and Other. Most of the material in this series was gathered by McKay in his lifetime. The material relating to McKay's death and burial was acquired by gift from his daughter after his death. Obituaries can be found within the Clippings subseries.
Series IV, Subject Files, housed in box 17, is organized into two subseries: Individuals and Organizations, and Topical. The Subject Files consist almost entirely of clippings, some from French newspapers, dating, when evident, from the late 1920s, but most from American papers dating from the mid and late 1930s. They reflect McKay's interests in liberal politics, labor issues and race, and reveal his continued interest in the countries in which he resided while abroad. There is overlap between the assigned subseries.
Series V, Photographs, housed in box 18, is organized into five subseries: Family, Snapshots of McKay, Other People, Places, and Other. There are some photographs of family and friends, but the two largest groups of photographs in this series are those taken while living and traveling abroad and studio portraits of well known musicians and figures in the African-American community. McKay was well received in Soviet Russia in the early 1920s and there are photographs of Lenin, Trotsky and other high ranking party officials, of McKay with members of the Russian Naval Academy and other groups, and of McKay addressing the Fourth Congress of the Communist International in the Throne Room at the Kremlin in Moscow. Many photographs of friends and photographs taken in Russia are inscribed to McKay. Most of the unidentified photographs in the Places subseries are probably of Morocco.
There are additional photographs in the Memorabilia series.
Series VI, Memorabilia, housed in box 19, is organized into five subseries: Material Relating to the Order of Jamaica Award, Material Relating to the McKay Tribute, Material Relating to the McKay Dedication, Material Relating to the McKay Centennial, and Material Relating to the McKay Conference. The first subseries consists of a photograph and copies of addresses made at the presentation of the Order of Jamaica awarded to McKay in 1978. The second subseries consists of printed material and clippings from the December 12, 1979 ceremony held at Claude McKay Secondary School, located in James Hill, Clarendon, Jamaica to celebrate the publication of My Green Hills of Jamaica. The third subseries consists of memorabilia from a memorial dedication held at the same school exactly one year later, on December 12, 1980. There are clippings, photographs, program materials and souvenirs, including t-shirts, pens and pencils, documenting the unveiling of a monument in his honor. The fourth subseries consists of printed material and clippings celebrating the centenary of McKay's birth. And the fifth subseries consists of printed material and photographs from an international conference on McKay sponsored by the Institute of Commonwealth and American Studies and English Language in India.
Oversize material, housed in box 20, includes items from Series I-VI. Restricted Fragile Papers are housed in box 21.
African American authors -- 20th Century -- Archives; American literature -- 20th Century; Authors, American -- 20th Century -- Archives; Harlem Renaissance -- Archives; Jamaican poetry -- 20th Century; Jamaica -- Poetry; Photographic prints; Audiovisual materials; Sound recordings; Authors; Poets; Studio portraits; Bontemps, Arna, 1902-1973; Bradley, William Aspenwall, 1878-1939; Brown, Sterling A., 1901-1989; Cartier-Bresson, Henri, 1908-2004; Cowl, Carl; Cullen, Countee, 1903-1946; Cunard, Nancy, 1896-1965; Dewey, John, 1859-1952; Dover, Cedric; Du Bois, W. E. B. (William Edward Burghardt), 1868-1963; Eastman, Max, 1883-1969; Fitzgerald, F. Scott (Francis Scott), 1896-1940; Ford, Charles Henri, 1908-2002; Hughes, Langston, 1902-1967; Jackman, Harold, 1901-1961; Johnson, James Weldon, 1871-1938; Locke, Alain, 1885-1954; McKay, Claude, 1890-1948; Powell, Adam Clayton, Jr., 1908-1972; Van Vechten, Carl, 1880-1964; Wilson, Edmund, 1895-1972
- Correspondence, 1923-90; Series I; 3.34; (8 boxes)
  Scope and Contents
  Series I, Correspondence, is organized into two subseries and arranged alphabetically within each subseries by name of correspondent.
  - GENERAL
    - "A" General, 1929-47 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - American Consular Service, 1928-30 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - The American Mercury, 1940, 1948 (Box 1, Folder 3)
      Includes letter to Carl Cowl
    - Anderson, Howard C., 1940 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Authors Club, 1937-41 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - "B" General, 1927-47 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Baldwin, Roger
      Related Archival Materials note
      See: Personal Service Fund, Box 5, folder 168
    - Barthé, Richmond (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Beirne, James A., 1944-45 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Bennett, Gwendolyn, 1937, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 9)
      Includes letter to Irita Van Doren
    - Bennett, Jo, 1925-28 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Binsfeld, Edmund, 1944-47 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Boardman, Helen, 1937, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Bontemps, Arna Wendell, 1941-52 (Box 1, Folder 13)
      Includes letters to Carl Cowl
    - Book Circle, 1944 (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - Bradley, William Aspenwall, 1927-34, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 15-18)
    - Brawley, Benjamin, 1937 (Box 1, Folder 19)
    - Britton, Betty, 1944-48, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 20-22)
    - Brown, Sterling Allen, 1938 Jan 27 (Box 1, Folder 23)
      See also: Federal Writers' Project, Box 3, folders 75-77
    - Buck, Pearl S. (Pearl Sydenstricker), 1947 (Box 1, Folder 24)
    - Budgen, Frank, 1930 (Box 1, Folder 25)
      Includes letter from McKay to Francine Budgen
    - Bullitt, Louise Bryant, 1926-30, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 26-28)
    - Burke, Selma, 1935-58, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 29)
    - Burrows, Edith, 1946-47 (Box 1, Folder 30)
    - "C" General, 1923-47 (Box 1, Folder 31-33)
    - Campbell, Grace, 1935-39 (Box 1, Folder 34)
    - Cartier-Bresson, Henri, 1933-35, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 35)
    - Catholic Youth Organization, 1946-48 (Box 2, Folder 36)
      Includes letter to Ruth Hope McKay Virtue
    - Chamberlain, John, 1937 Sep 18 (Box 2, Folder 37)
    - Churchill, Peter, 1939 (Box 2, Folder 38)
    - Cooper, Rachel McKay, 1927-29 (Box 2, Folder 39)
    - Counts, George S., 1944 (Box 2, Folder 40)
    - Cowl, Carl, 1941-48, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 41-50)
      Includes contract and enclosures from Cedric Dover, Herbert Weinstock and John Woodburn
      See also: Leonard, Claire, Box 5, folder 134
    - Cowl, Carl (letters to others), 1947-52 (Box 2, Folder 51-52)
    - Cullen, Countee, 1927-43, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 53)
    - Cunard, Nancy, 1932-33, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 54-57)
    - "D" General, 1938 Jun 15 (Box 2, Folder 58)
    - Day, Dorothy, 1944-47, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 59)
    - Dehn, Adolf, 1934 Sep 23 (Box 2, Folder 60)
    - Dewey, John, 1940-47, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 61)
      Includes letters to Carl Cowl and introduction to Selected Poems
    - Donovan, Vincent C., 1945 (Box 2, Folder 62)
    - Dover, Cedric, 1946-52, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 63-64)
      Includes letter to Carl Cowl and synopsis to Singing Brown
    - Du Bois, W. E. B. (William Edward Burghardt), 1927, 1935 (Box 2, Folder 65)
    - "E" General, 1940-44 (Box 2, Folder 66)
    - Eastman, Max, 1926-50, n.d. (Box 3, Folder 67-71)
      Includes poems and correspondence with "Eliena," Carl Cowl and U.S. Office of War Information
    - Embree, Edwin R. (Edwin Rogers), 1937 Mar 8 (Box 3, Folder 72)
      See also: Julius Rosenwald Fund, Box 4, folder 125
    - "F" General, 1926-45 (Box 3, Folder 73-74)
    - Fadiman, Clifton
      See: Simon and Schuster, Inc., Box 8, folder 280
    - Federal Writers' Project, 1935-37 (Box 3, Folder 75-77)
      See also: Brown, Sterling Allen, Box 1, folder 23
    - Federal Writers' Project (N.Y.), 1935-38 (Box 3, Folder 78-79)
      See also: United States. Works Progress Administration (N.Y.), Box 7, folder 210
    - Fitzgerald, F. Scott (Francis Scott), 1928 Jun 18 (Box 3, Folder 80)
    - Flodin, Jack, 1947 Oct 9 (Box 3, Folder 81)
    - Ford, Charles Henri, 1935-38, n.d. (Box 3, Folder 82)
      Includes poems
    - Friedmann, Georges, 1927-30, n.d. (Box 3, Folder 83)
      See also: Éditions Rieder, Box 8, folder 261
    - "G" General, 1930-48 (Box 3, Folder 84-85)
    - Gallery of Living Catholic Authors, 1947-48 (Box 3, Folder 86)
    - Gannett, Lewis, 1935-37 (Box 3, Folder 87)
    - Gilmore, Reuben, 1934-41 (Box 3, Folder 88)
    - Gregory, Horace, 1937 Sep 18 (Box 3, Folder 89)
    - Guilloux, Louis, 1931 Jun 1 (Box 3, Folder 90)
    - "H" General, 1926-40, n.d. (Box 3, Folder 91)
    - Hackett, Harold W., 1946-48 (Box 3, Folder 92)
    - Halper, Albert, 1935-36 (Box 3, Folder 93)
    - Hamilton, Hollister Adelbert, 1934-38 (Box 3, Folder 94)
    - Harmon Foundation, Inc., 1929-38 (Box 3, Folder 95)
    - Hennacy, Ammon, 1946-47, n.d. (Box 3, Folder 96)
    - Huff, William Henry, 1944-47, n.d. (Box 3, Folder 97)
    - Hughes, Langston, 1925-48, n.d. (Box 3, Folder 98-99)
      Includes card to Carl Cowl
    - "I" General, 1944 (Box 3, Folder 100)
    - Ingram, Rex, 1928, n.d. (Box 3, Folder 101)
    - "J" General, 1929-40 (Box 4, Folder 102)
    - Jackman, Harold, 1927-44, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 103-109)
    - Jackman, Ivie A., 1944-47 (Box 4, Folder 110-111)
    - James Weldon Johnson Literary Guild, 1936-39 (Box 4, Folder 112)
    - Jewish Frontier, 1938-47 (Box 4, Folder 113)
    - John Simon Guggenheim Memorial Foundation, 1933-38 (Box 4, Folder 114-116)
    - Johnson, Charles Spurgeon, 1937 Sep 16 (Box 4, Folder 117)
    - Johnson, James Weldon, 1928-40, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 118-122)
      Includes correspondence with Grace Nail Johnson and Max Eastman and manuscript titled "Claude McKay"
    - Jones, St. Clair, 1937 Mar 16 (Box 4, Folder 123)
    - Joyce, Edward, 1946-48 (Box 4, Folder 124)
    - Julius Rosenwald Fund, 1935-36 (Box 4, Folder 125)
      See also: Embree, Edwin R. (Edwin Rogers), Box 3, folder 72
    - "K" General, 1928-44 (Box 4, Folder 126)
    - Kienberger, V. F., 1944-48 (Box 4, Folder 127)
      Includes enclosure from Catherine Doherty
    - King, Rosanna, 1947-48, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 128)
    - Klein, Marie, 1946-47, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 129)
    - Krutch, Joseph Wood, 1937 Sep 9 (Box 4, Folder 130)
    - "L" General, 1930-44 (Box 4, Folder 131)
    - La Farge, John, 1937 Jun 4 (Box 5, Folder 132)
    - League of American Writers, 1937, n.d. (Box 5, Folder 133)
    - Leonard, Claire, 1947 (Box 5, Folder 134)
      Includes contract
      See also: Cowl, Carl, Box 2, folders 41-50
    - Lewis, Sinclair, 1925 Jan 10 (Box 5, Folder 135)
      Includes carbon to Roger Baldwin
      See also: Personal Service Fund, Box 5, folder 168
    - Library of Congress, 1939 Jun 4 (Box 5, Folder 136)
    - Lieber, Maxim, 1935 (Box 5, Folder 137)
    - Locke, Alain LeRoy, 1927-30 (Box 5, Folder 138)
    - "M" General, 1927-48 (Box 5, Folder 139-140)
    - McCord, David Frederick
      See: Raphael, Ruth, Box 6, folder 174
    - McKay, T. E., 1929-36 (Box 5, Folder 141-142)
      Includes enclosure from Rhue (Ruth) Hope McKay Virtue
    - McKay, U. Theo, 1929-33 (Box 5, Folder 143)
    - MacLeish, Archibald, 1941-42 (Box 5, Folder 144)
    - Mandel, Benjamin, 1939 Sep 28 (Box 5, Folder 145)
    - Marciniak, Ed, 1944-47, n.d. (Box 5, Folder 146)
      See also: Work, Box 7, folder 234
    - Marshall, Russell, 1944-47 (Box 5, Folder 147)
    - Mencken, H. L. (Henry Louis), 1935 Nov 5 (Box 5, Folder 148)
    - Moon, Henry Lee, 1938 May 17 (Box 5, Folder 149)
    - "N" General, 1935-46 (Box 5, Folder 150)
    - The Nation, 1934-47, n.d. (Box 5, Folder 151-153)
      Includes enclosure from The Spoken Word and poems
    - National Association for the Advancement of Colored People, 1940, 1945 (Box 5, Folder 154)
    - New Jersey. Bureau of Vital Statistics, 1929 Sep 17 (Box 5, Folder 155)
      Includes copy of McKay's marriage certificate
    - New Leader, 1938-44 (Box 5, Folder 156-157)
    - New Masses, 1926 Apr 28 (Box 5, Folder 158)
    - The New Republic, 1938 Jul 27 (Box 5, Folder 159)
    - New York Amsterdam News, 1926-39, n.d. (Box 5, Folder 160)
      Includes "Earl"
    - New York Public Library, 1934-40 (Box 5, Folder 161)
    - Nussbaum, Anna, 1928 (Box 5, Folder 162)
    - "O" General, 1935-37 (Box 5, Folder 163)
    - Opportunity, 1926-39, n.d. (Box 5, Folder 164)
      Includes letter to The Afro- American
    - Otis, William Bradley, 1937, n.d. (Box 5, Folder 165)
      Includes book fragment with presentation inscription
    - Ovington, Mary W., 1935 Feb 24 (Box 5, Folder 166)
    - "P" General, 1940-46 (Box 5, Folder 167)
    - Personal Service Fund, 1925-37, n.d. (Box 5, Folder 168)
      Includes letters to Max Eastman and Sinclair Lewis
    - Posselt, Erich, 1934 Nov 30 (Box 5, Folder 169)
      Letter to Max Eastman
    - Powell, Adam Clayton, 1944 Jun 5 (Box 5, Folder 170)
    - "R" General, 1932-46 (Box 5, Folder 171)
    - Rabearivelo, J. J., 1932 Dec 13 (Box 6, Folder 172)
    - Randolph, A. Philip, 1940-42 (Box 6, Folder 173)
    - Raphael, Ruth, 1937-44 (Box 6, Folder 174)
      Includes enclosures from James S. Watson and [George?] Schuyler to David Frederick McCord
    - Roberti, Jacques, 1931 Sep 22 (Box 6, Folder 175)
    - Roberts, Laurence, 1935-39 (Box 6, Folder 176-178)
      Includes enclosures from E. Sylvia Pankhurst and Lee Furman Inc.
    - Roger, José, 1930-32 (Box 6, Folder 179)
    - Rooney, Donald J., 1945-48 (Box 6, Folder 180-181)
    - Rozmarin, Joe, 1945, n.d. (Box 6, Folder 182)
    - "S" General, 1934-48 (Box 6, Folder 183-186)
    - Salem, Hanem, 1934-38, n.d. (Box 6, Folder 187-188)
    - San Diego County General Hospital, 1946-47 (Box 6, Folder 189)
    - Saposnekow, J., 1944 (Box 6, Folder 190)
    - Saunders, Marion, 1940-41 (Box 6, Folder 191)
    - Schomburg, Arthur Alfonso, 1925-35 (Box 6, Folder 192)
    - Schreiber, G. R., 1946 (Box 6, Folder 193)
    - Sheil, Bernard J. (Bernard James), 1944-46 (Box 6, Folder 194)
    - Smith, Charles C.
      See: Catholic Youth Organization, Box 2, folder 36
    - Smyth, Carlisle, 1940-41 (Box 6, Folder 195)
    - Spingarn, Arthur B., 1937 May 10 (Box 6, Folder 196)
    - Spingarn, J. E., 1933, 1937 (Box 6, Folder 197)
    - Sterling, Helen, 1934-40, n.d. (Box 6, Folder 198)
      Includes poem
    - Stillman, Clara G., 1936 Mar (Box 6, Folder 199)
    - Stolberg, Benjamin, 1940 Dec (Box 6, Folder 200)
    - Studin, Charles H., 1934-37 (Box 6, Folder 201)
    - "T" General, 1930-46, n.d. (Box 6, Folder 202)
    - Tarry, Ellen, 1940-48 (Box 6, Folder 203-204)